Guide to the Willem J. Kolff audio-visual collection 1949-1995
Multimedia Archives, J. Willard Marriott Library, University of Utah
- Miscellaneous items, 1949-1995
  - 119 Folders of Magnetic Dictaphone Cards covering a variety of topics., undated; dictaphone card (Card 121)
    See Folders for further information.
  - Legacy of life: Willem J. Kolff, M.D., Ph. D. part 1, 1995 March 23; VHS videocassette (Cassette 122)
    LDS Hospital Media Services. 1 hour 28 minutes.
  - Legacy of life Willem J. Kolff, M.D., Ph. D. part 2, 1995 March 23; VHS videocassette (Cassette 123)
    LDS Hospital Media Services. 15 minutes.
  - National Inventors Hall of Fame ceremony, 1985; Betacam videocassette (Cassette 124)
  - National Inventors Hall of Fame, 1993 April 24; VHS videocassette (Cassette 125)
    Induction ceremony (Akron, Ohio). 1 hour 40 minutes.
  - National Inventors Hall of Fame, 23 April 1994; VHS videocassette (Cassette 126)
    >Induction ceremony (Akron, Ohio). 1 hour 45 minutes.
  - Thoracoscopic breathing pacemaker surgery, DoBelle, 1994 November 03; VHs videocassette (Cassette 127)
  - A history of extra corporeal circulation, 1990; VHS videocassette (Cassette 128)
    PSICOR Incirca Production. 44 minutes
  - Dr. B. Lott: History of renal dialysis, 1991; VHS videocassette (Cassette 129)
  - Implantation of the GORE-TEX peritoneal catheter, 1983; Betacam videocassette (Cassette 130)
  - Dutch interview with Dr. Kolff, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 131)
    The tape is an interview in Dutch about Kolff's years in Kampen by Rie Hulsmann-Gosen. It was made in 1991. The envelope containing the cassette also contains a copy of a letter about the cassette
  - Dr. W.J. Kolff's induction into Beehive Hall of Fame in Salt Lake City, 1983 September 28; VHS videocassette (Cassette 132)
  - Dialysis in wonderland, 1979; 1982 June 7-15; VHS videocassette (Cassette 133)
    Grand Canyon: June 7-15, 1982
    Colorado River, Moab, Utah: 1979
    From a copy from Mr. John Warner.
  - State-Of-The-Art lecture: Persisting medical problems in dialysis treatment, are there any solutions?, 26 April 1994; VHS videocassette (Cassette 134)
    J. Bergstrom, John P. Peters Award.
  - Kidney transplant patients on Dr. Kolff's farm, 1964; VHS videocassette (Cassette 135)
    Cleveland, Ohio
  - Farm sequence of patients after kidney transplantation, 1964 August 24; 1990 September 13; VHS videocassette (Cassette 136)
    Recorded on September 13, 1990 in Cleveland, Ohio.
  - Kidney dialysis presentation by Sarah Goldberg, undated; VHS videocassette (Cassette 137)
  - Dialysis Pioneer's dinner (Rottach), 1986; VHS videocassette (Cassette 138)
  - Four films narrated by Dr. W. J. Kolff, undated; VHS videocassette (Cassette 139)
    Artificial Kidney for the Treatment of Serious Uremia
    Disposable Coil Kidney
    Single Needle Dialysis
    Towards a Wearable Artificial Kidney
  - Markant, 1989 November 15; U-matic videocassette (Cassette 140)
    Dutch film with English inserts by Dr. Kolff.
    Kolff-narrated version recorded November 15, 1989.
  - Artificial eye, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 141)
    This audiocassette contains an interview with a patient who had an artificial eye inserted and an interview with the doctor who performs the same type of procedures. The patient talks about the time and incident in which he lost his eye sight as well as the sensation of having surgery while still awake. He also talks about recognition by sight verses recognition by touch and he discusses the change in speed of his reading before and after his surgery. The Physician talks about the future possibilities for further improving the patients eye sight, explains the procedure in simplified terms and discusses the role of computers in eye surgery.
  - Vacuum Formed Heart: Implantation of I7V7, 1984 February 23; VHS videocassette (Cassette 142)